# MAXIM SHOLONIK

# Frontend developer



- Belarus, Brest (ready to relocate or work remotely)
- +375 (33) 674-14-14
- makcsholonik@gmail.com









#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a person who has a strong passion for programming. I have experience in with React, Redux, creating SPA TypeScript. Now I am improving my skills in this direction and expanding them withnew technologies. I spend my leisure time on Codewars or with educational books. Open for your suggestions.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### FRONTEND DEVELOPER Freelance Sep. 2021 - present

- -Taking part in creating learning app, developed login page, modal windows, tests, menu, and design;
- -Using the following developer technologies: React, Redux, ReduxThunk, RestAPI, Axios, Formik, MaterialUI, etc;
- -Migration to Typescript;
- -Work with Hooks;
- -Performance enhancement (memo, useCallback, lazy, Suspense etc.);
- -Checking the correctness of the code with Unit Tests, applying Storybook fordemonstration of individual modules of the application.

#### SALES MANAGER PP Polesie JV, Ltd. Oct. 2016 - Jan. 2022

- -Selling plastic toys, meeting sales targets;
- -Carried out negotiations with company's clients and prospects;
- -Successfully managed accounts receivable;
- -On the regular basis tracked and analyzed sales
- -Assisted the management team with sales analytics and decisions concerning sales strategy;
- -Participated in toy fairs;
- -Coached and supervised merchandisers.

#### EDUCATION

FRONTEND DEVELOPER (React + Redux, TS) IT-incubator.by 2020 - 2021

**ECONOMIST** Belorussian trade-economic university of consumer cooperation 2010-2015

## SKILLS

- React
- Redux
- TypeScript
- REST API
- Unit tests
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- English (Å1) Russian (Native)